(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
DREAM CATCHER
Hakos Baelz Birthday Live 2024
A BEGINNING
There was once a little rat that dreamed.
She dreamed of a life filled with her loves:
singing, dancing, and anime.
Bae! Dinner time!
Oh!
半端なら K.O.
If you're half-hearted, you're K.O.
ふわふわしたいなら DANZA
If you want to feel light, then dance!
火炎準備さあ O.K.
Ready the flames, okay?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether I cry or laugh, love me, all right?
踊 / Lyrics: DECO*27 / Composition: Giga / TeddyLoid
Odori / Lyrics: DECO*27 / Composition: Giga / TeddyLoid
ほら SEINO 手を響かせろ
Come on, one-two! Clap your hands!
難解となってつまんない 事もあるでしょう
I'm sure there are times when things get complicated and boring.
ロンリー・ロンリーなの？ 案外本気出そう
Are you lonely-lonely? Let's get surprisingly serious.
嫌んなっちゃって泥に 吐くほどだろうが
Even if you're sick of it and vomit in the mud,
溺れ堕ちてゆけ
Go ahead and drown in it.
それそれ行こうか
Come on, let's go!
もっと頑張って 渇望にもっと頑張って
Try harder, try harder for your cravings!
繋がるわ 一人より二人 増えたら安心 心配ないや
We're connected; two is better than one.
More people means peace of mind, no worries!
All right 任せてどんまい 甘い甘いな みんなで乗っかっちゃえば
All right, leave it to me, don't mind.
How sweet, if we all jump on together...
ほら案外 スパッとイッちゃいそう
Look, it'll probably go smoothly!
半端なら K.O.
If you're half-hearted, you're K.O.
ふわふわしたいなら DANZA
If you want to feel light, then dance!
火炎準備さあ O.K.
Ready the flames, okay?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether I cry or laugh, love me, all right?
ほら SEINO 手を響かせろ
Come on, one-two! Clap your hands!
Rampampam...
踊りだせ、踊りだせ / 孤独を割け　間に寄れ
Dance away, dance away / Split the solitude, follow me
痛みまで教えて / 心でバイバイ let go
Tell me even your pain / Let go with a 'bye bye' in your heart
Here we go!
どんなレッツゴー　ガンダッドン / 理想狂の化粧番です
Any kind of let's go, gun-da-don / It's a mad idealist's make-up shift
最高で掴んでしまうでしょう　A-yeah
I'll probably grab it at its best, A-yeah
Up and down　脳内 attention / 目回っちゃってるの　そっと
Up and down, attention in my brain / I'm getting dizzy, quietly
ドバっと吹き出すのは本音の独り言
What's gushing out is a monologue of true feelings
別に興味ない
I'm not particularly interested
特に関係ない
It doesn't really matter
塞ぎ込んで鉄砲脱腸べ
Shutting myself in, a gun and a hernia
合図は奏でて bra-bra-bra-play
The signal is playing, bra-bra-bra-play
ほら集まって夜光だ Hey-yay
Look, gather around, it's a nocturnal light, Hey-yay
泣いていこう
Let's keep crying
Rampampam...
世間！ Rampampam...
Society! Rampampam...
合羽なら K.O.!
If it's a raincoat, K.O.!
Woah woah woah...
踊りだせ、踊りだせ / 孤独を割け　間に寄れ
Dance away, dance away / Split the solitude, follow me
痛みまで教えて / 今宵はアッテンパーティだ
Tell me even your pain / Tonight is an up-and-down party
上っ面残して化けた fu-fu-fu
Left the superficiality and transformed, fu-fu-fu
次回までお元気で / 心でバイバイ let go
Stay well until next time / Let go with a 'bye bye' in your heart
Bye bye! Thank you, thank you, thank you!
WHAT'S UP!
I am Chaos, the end of end,
a still birth trapped in a cage of ice,
your best friend Hakos Baelz from hololive English!
我はカオス、終わりの果て
I am Chaos, the end of end,
ザ・エンド。氷の檻に踏み去りし黒金の薔薇
The End. A jet-black rose left behind in a cage of ice.
汝の友、ホロライブのハコス・ベールズです！
Your friend, Hakos Baelz from hololive!
Witness me!
Guys, it's finally, finally, finally my birthday!
It is finally my... Do you understand?
It's been... it's finally my birthday!
Welcome to my Birthday Live 2024,
DREAMCATCHER!
I'm so thankful that I could do a birthday live
for my real birthday this year.
And I have a special, special stage made for it,
which I'll talk about in a second.
But please use the hashtag #BaeDay2024
to share your comments, and your thoughts,
and screenshots, and anything,
cause I'm going to be reading it after the stream.
Thank you so much!
I'm so excited! Look at this stage!
I had an original stage design! Oh my god!
We've got the butterfly,
we've got the water and fire!
How does that work? Nobody knows!
It's so chuuni, I love it!
Wee!
かっこいいでしょう？
Isn't it cool?
へへへ...
Hehehe...
Thank you so much for helping me design this stage!
It's so cool!
I'm... I'm so excited,
I can't... I can't get anything out.
But we have a lot of guests performing today,
and we have a lot of songs,
so you might not see MC Bae as much.
It's gonna be song after song after song after song!
So get ready! You're not ready!
But also stay until the very end
because I have a very important announcement.
Yeah, not a little announcement,
a big important announcement
that you will never guess.
はい！配信も最後まで見てていけたら嬉しいなと思ってます！
Yes! I hope you can watch the stream until the end!
発表がありますので。はい、普通の発表じゃなくて...
Since there is an announcement. It's not a normal one...
重大な発表があります！
There is a major announcement!
なので、最後までお楽しみみ～げ～！
So, please enjoy until the end!
This is a very special birthday live to me.
It kind of marks my journey throughout hololive,
and my journey as an idol.
So there's a lot of... there might be some lore,
there might be a few important and special guests,
and some special songs that I hope you all enjoy!
So I'm just so excited! I'm just so excited!
And I'm going to go get ready!
the next song and...
...I hope you all enjoy.
はい！次の曲、ちょっと準備にいきたいと思いますので...
Alright! I'm going to go get ready for the next song, so...
...お楽しみに！
...please look forward to it!
じゃ、あとでね。
Well then, see you in a bit.
Okay! Okay!
Bye bye! Bye bye! Bye bye!
行ってきます！バイバイ！
I'm off! Bye bye!
Alchemy / Lyrics・Composition: 麻枝 准
Alchemy / Lyrics・Composition: Jun Maeda
無限に生きたい
I want to live forever
無限に生きられたら
If only I could live forever
全てかなう
Everything would come true
でも いろんなものが
But so many things...
アタシを追い越してく
...are passing me by
生き残り時間を
The time I have left to live...
夢の座標の行方
...and the coordinates of my dreams
全部大事なものなのに
Even though they're all so important to me
いっさ ここらでちょっと
So let's take a break here...
甘いもの食べていこう
...and eat something sweet
そういう思考停止
Stopping my thoughts like that...
ばかり得意になった
...is all I've become good at
歩いてきた道振り返ると
When I look back at the path I've walked
嫌なことばかりで
It's full of unpleasant things...
もう うんざりだよ
...and I'm sick of it
触れるものを輝かせていく
Making everything I touch shine
そんな道を歩きたい
That's the kind of path I want to live
あたしだよ
It's me
一生に生きたい
I want to live my whole life
褪せてばかりの日々
In these days full of impatience
全て消えそう
Everything seems like it'll vanish
でも さぼってみる
But I'll try slacking off...
だって 疲れちゃうじゃない
...because I'll just get tired otherwise
そんな矛盾思考
Such contradictory thoughts...
アタシ頭どっか
...I'm just overthinking it all
知らないうちに
Before I knew it...
歌みたいだ
...it's like a song
いっさ ここらでちょっと
So let's take a break here...
酔いへいいとこ
...and enjoy the evening
ずっと起きてられる
I can stay awake forever...
薬 頂けませんか
...can I have some medicine for that?
ぼさっと突っ立ってるだけでも
Even if I'm just standing there blankly...
化石になってしまいそうなんだよ
...I feel like I'm going to turn into a fossil
誰からも忘れられたような
Like I've been forgotten by everyone...
かすかな存在になってしまうよ
...becoming a faint existence
いっさ ここらでちょっと
So let's take a break here...
根性を見せてやる
...and show some guts
自分で頬叩いて
Slapping my own cheeks...
存在の証明
...as proof of my existence
歩いてきた道振り返らない
I won't look back at the path I've walked
嫌なことばかりでも前進め
Even if it's full of unpleasant things, move forward
触れるものを輝かせていく
Making everything I touch shine
そんな存在になっていく
I'll become that kind of person
見せるよ
I'll show you
A WISH
(Exhales)
(Gasps)
Ow!
(Groaning)
Oh?
(Gasps) Whoa!
And so, she stumbled...
...into a magical place.
ロキ / Lyrics・Composition：みきとP
Roki / Lyrics・Composition: Mikito-P
さあ　日進月歩
Come on, making steady progress
いいや　唯我独尊
No, being the only one
惑星探査　代わる代わる
Planetary exploration, one after another
パチッと目が覚めたら　サヨナラボーイ
Waking up with a snap, goodbye boy
アルバイトはナカノの元
Part-time job at Nakano's place
海岸にはエティチュード
An attitude on the coast
人見知り宣言で逃げるピカボーイ
A Pikaboy escaping with a shyness declaration
ゆとりぼっちゃんの　坊ちゃんの
You privileged spoiled brat
金も　才能も　なまじっか
With just a little bit of money and talent
あるだけ　厄介です
It's more of a hassle than anything
Boys, be ambitious...
...like this old man
長い前髪　君　誰の信者？
With that long fringe, whose believer are you?
信者
Believer
勘違いすんな　教祖はお前だ
Don't get it wrong, you are the guru
ロキロキの　ロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
かき鳴らす　エレクトリック・ギターは
Strumming the electric guitar...
Don't stop! Don't stop!
さあ　君のすべてを
Come on, show me everything of yours
曝け出してみせろよ
Bare it all to me
ロキロキの　ロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
さあ　日進月歩
Come on, making steady progress
自称メンヘラ　人気の割に
Self-proclaimed "menhera", considering your popularity...
そんなにないから　色々大変ですね
You don't have much, so it must be tough
はっきり言なよ　匿名アイコン
Come on, say it clearly, anonymous icon
はっきり見せなよ　自社のアイコン
Come on, show it clearly, company icon
愛し子いとしで　自意識マダボーイ
Cherished child, self-conscious "Mada-Boy"
ぶっちゃけ　どんだけ　賢く　あざとく　やったって
To be honest, no matter how cleverly and cunningly you do it
10年後には　メイクも　落ちてんだよ
Ten years from now, your makeup will have faded
Boys, be ambitious...
...like this old man
生き抜くためだ　決めろ、テイク・ア・セルフィー
It's for the sake of survival, come on, take a selfie
セルフィー
Selfie
死ぬんじゃねえぞ　お互いにな
Don't you go and die, both of us
ロキロキの　ロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
薄っぺらい　ラブソングでもいい
Even a shallow love song is fine
Don't stop! Don't stop!
目の前の　あの子を
That girl in front of you...
沸かしてみせろよ
Show me you can make her fired up
ロキロキの　ロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
お化粧直して　満足できない
I can't be satisfied with just touching up my makeup
不自由にはこばれた　素顔とは
A bare face that's been carried in bondage...
足し、足し、プレッシャーで　いっぱい
Filled with added pressure
実は昨日から風邪で声が出ません
Actually, I've had a cold since yesterday and can't use my voice
は？
Ha?
ん？
Hmm?
は？
Ha?
寝不足はあてていいよ　ベイビー
It's okay to make up for lack of sleep, baby
ベイビー
Baby
死ぬんじゃねえぞ　お互いにな
Don't you go and die, both of us
ロキロキの　ロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
かき鳴らす　エレクトリック・ギターは
Strumming the electric guitar...
Don't stop! Don't stop!
さあ　君のすべてを
Come on, show me everything of yours
曝け出してみせろよ
Bare it all to me
ロキロキの　ロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rock n' Rock n' Roll
ロキロキの
Roki Roki's...
ロックンロックンロール
Rock n' Rock n' Roll
死ぬんじゃねえぞ
Don't you go and die
死にたかねえのは
The one who doesn't want to die is...
お互い様
Both of us
君と一緒に　いがいちばん
Being with you is the best
好きよってもっと　ぎゅっとね
I love you, so hold me tighter
君を新しい場所へと
To a new place with you...
引っぱってっちゃう
...I'll pull you along
る・らんら！　遅れないでね
ru-ranra! Don't be late
すーぱー・あふぇくしょん
Super Affection
飛んできすごいな　だれが？
Fly away, it's amazing. Who is it?
私達でしょ　線引きのないの
It's us, isn't it? Without boundaries
イヤッホー　楽しい宴
Yippee! A fun banquet
絶対終わらない魔法かけて
Cast a spell that never ends
ドキドキの前夜祭
A heart-pounding eve festival
遊んで遊んで　ばかりでいいな
It's fine to just play and play
でしょやっぱやっぱそうでしょ
Right? After all, that's right
お祭りわっしょいで仲良し
Festival 'wasshoi', we're friends
仲良し
Friends
君へのわっしょいは自然体
My 'wasshoi' to you is natural
アフェクション
Affection
お出かけの順調は
Getting ready to go out smoothly
スイッチ入ってハイになって寛容だ
Switching on, getting high, and being tolerant
甘いデリカシーで
With sweet delicacy
ほんのりさっぱりがっつり恋しちゃう
A little, refreshing, and thoroughly falling in love
君と一緒に　いがいちばん
Being with you is the best
好きよってもっと　ぎゅっとね
I love you, so hold me tighter
君を新しい場所へと
To a new place with you
引っぱってっちゃう　る・らんら！
I'll pull you along, ru-ranra!
ホント　一緒にいたいな
Really, I want to be together
邪魔されたくないんだもん
I don't want to be disturbed
君に秘密の場所では
In a secret place for you
張り切っちゃうよ　るらんら　るらんら　だよ
I'll give it my all, ru-ranra, ru-ranra
ボイコットしないで　だれの？
Don't boycott. Whose?
君たちの拍手　大切な合図
Your applause, an important signal
イヤッホー　うれしい集い
Yippee! A happy gathering
断然おもしろいはずだから
Because it's definitely going to be fun
好き好きの感謝祭
A thanksgiving for all the things I love
回って回って　みせてよほらね
Spin and spin, show me, see?
すごいやっぱりですごい
Amazing, as expected, it's amazing
過激なわっしょいでパワフル
Powerful with an extreme 'wasshoi'
ミラクル
Miracle
私もわっしょいで保険室
Me too, with 'wasshoi', in the nurse's office
保険室
Nurse's office
お休みのコールは
The 'good night' call is
スウィートずっともっと関係だ
A sweet, eternal relationship
ゆるいデリバリーが
A loose delivery
やんわりおっとりぷっくり恋なんだ
Is a soft, gentle, and plump love
あのね　応援させてよ
You know, let me cheer you on
いつだってやっぱ元気に
Always energetic after all
あのさ　踊りたいこのとき
Hey, I want to dance at this moment
おいてっちゃってじだんだ踏む？
If I leave you behind, will you stamp your feet?
本気　応援したいな
Seriously, I want to cheer you on
落ち込みたくないんだもん
I don't want to feel down
あのね　冒険夢みて
You know, dreaming of adventure
知らないフリじだんだじだんだだね
Pretending not to know, stamping your feet
君と一緒に　いがいちばん
Being with you is the best
好きよってもっと　ぎゅっとね
I love you, so hold me tighter
君を新しい場所へと
To a new place with you
引っぱってっちゃう　る・らんらして
Pulling you along, ru-ranra
ホント　一緒にいたいな
Really, I want to be together
邪魔されたくないんだもん
I don't want to be disturbed
君に秘密の場所では
In a secret place for you
張り切っちゃうよ　るらんら？　る・らんら！　だよ　だよ
I'll give it my all, ru-ranra? ru-ranra! Yes, yes
この混沌とした令和のインターネットを照らす一筋の光
A single ray of light illuminating this chaotic Reiwa internet
電子の海を漂うオタクに笑顔を
Bringing smiles to otaku drifting through the sea of electrons
未来の平和 ＼＼＼マックス／／／
Future peace MAX
躁鬱だけど　任せとけ
I'm manic-depressive, but leave it to me
インターネットエンジェル　ただいま降臨
Internet Angel, descending now
INTERNET OVERDOSE
社会をやめろ　家族をやめろ
Quit society, quit your family
人間関係をやめろ
Quit human relationships
今すぐ薄暗い部屋で　青白いライトを浴びろ
Right now, in a dim room, bask in the pale light
大丈夫　怖かったこと　全部上書きするからね
It's okay, I'll overwrite everything that was scary
現実を...
Reality...
crazy for you
おかしくなりそうなほど情報過多のインターネット
The internet's info overload is driving me crazy
今助けてあげるよ Darling, Darling
I'll save you now, Darling, Darling
嘘も本当も見抜けるし
I can see through both lies and truth
この愛暴走しちゃうし
This love is going out of control
壊れてしまうけど
Even if I end up breaking
考えなくていいんだよ
You don't have to think anymore
もうすぐ楽になるから
Because it'll all be easier soon
脳内に放射するポイズンレディオ
Poison Radio radiating in your brain
麻薬より甘いよ
Sweeter than any drug
赤い唇がDANGEROUS
Red lips are dangerous
飲み干して剥き出したナイフ突き刺さる
Drink it all up and the bare knife stabs
恋愛の景色 奇跡なら無意識
The landscape of love, if it's a miracle, it's unconscious
遥か異国のランデヴー
A rendezvous in a far-off foreign land
真珠の煌めきで
With the sparkle of pearls
愛に引きずられて
Dragged along by love
琥珀色の吐息に消えた
Vanished into an amber breath
砂漠さえも満たしたい
I want to fill even the desert
熱くVENUS
Hotly, Venus
燃えてVENUS
Burning, Venus
星のデルタ夜空を染め
The star's delta dyes the night sky
サザンクロス揺れる大地
The Southern Cross, the shaking earth
指先で見つめたい
I want to gaze with my fingertips
熱くVENUS
Hotly, Venus
感じてVENUS
Feel it, Venus
稲妻より光見せて
Show me a light brighter than lightning
蜃気楼操る空に
In the sky manipulating mirages
愛の輝き 放て
Release the radiance of love
先輩たち！
Senpais!
歌ったるぞ！
We're gonna sing!
チョー待て待て待て、この曲踊ったことねえっすよ！
Wait, wait, wait, wait! I've never danced to this song!
最高の時間にしようぜ！
Let's make this the best time ever!
READY...
GO!
熱くVENUS
Hotly, Venus
燃えてVENUS
Burning, Venus
君の瞳が胸を焦がす
Your eyes scorch my chest
シルクロード愛は旋律
Silk Road, love is a melody
躊躇うなら忘れたい
If I hesitate, I want to forget
熱くVENUS
Hotly, Venus
燃えてVENUS
Burning, Venus
星のデルタ夜空を染め
The star's delta dyes the night sky
サザンクロス揺れる大地
The Southern Cross, the shaking earth
指先で見つめたい
I want to gaze with my fingertips
熱くVENUS
Hotly, Venus
感じてVENUS
Feel it, Venus
稲妻より光見せて
Show me a light brighter than lightning
蜃気楼操る空に
In the sky manipulating mirages
愛の輝き 放て
Release the radiance of love
泥中に咲く
Blooming in the Mud
Lyrics・Composition: 針原翼 (HarryP)
Lyrics & Composition: Harry Haruhara (HarryP)
Arrangement: 棚橋テルアキ
Arrangement: Teruaki Tanahashi
砕けた心が濾過できなくて
My broken heart couldn't be filtered
涙はそっと枯れてゆく
The tears gently wither away
もう一粒も流れなくて
Not even one more drop will flow
おかしいよねって笑ってる
I'm laughing, saying, "It's strange, isn't it?"
酷烈な人生 あなたを最に
A harsh life, with you at the end
迷路の径路 濁世の闇
The path of the maze, the darkness of this corrupt world
立ちはだかる ああ君は誰よりも憂う人
Blocking the way, ah, you are the one who grieves more than anyone
だから今僕らは溺れかけてる
That's why we're drowning now
寸前だろう 正しい呼吸に救われた
It must be the brink; I was saved by a proper breath
今はいつか死ぬために生きてる
Now I live for the sake of dying someday
だけだ
That's all
雨が嫌いな理由を知ると
When I learn the reason why I hate the rain
深いところで思い出すこと
The things I remember deep down
泡粒のシャボン玉なら
If they were bubbles from a soapy sphere
きっとふわふわでしとしと
I'm sure they'd be fluffy and moist
地面の色を見て歩く 水溜りのない場所選んでる
Walking while looking at the color of the ground, choosing a place without puddles
さては不遇の道を逸れるため 自己防衛だってするんでしょう
So, to avoid the path of misfortune, you'd even resort to self-defense, wouldn't you?
僕はいま人間です 今日も明日もその次の日も
I am human now, today, tomorrow, and the day after that too
その暗い手で
With those dark hands
みんな別々の行き先を食べてる
Everyone is consuming different destinations
さあ君も今人間で　その姿が
Now you, too, are human, and just because
嫌いなだけで
you hate that form
憎めないよ　優しいから
I can't hate you, because you're kind
君は誰のために物願うと
For whom do you make your prayers?
一片の羽が散るために
In order for a single feather to fall
水も土も光もその形も
The water, the soil, the light, and that shape, too
僕の目の前にあるものが
The things right before my eyes
その意味も過去も未来も
Their meaning, their past, and their future
ひと時とかけろ止まれないで
Gamble on a single moment, don't stop
僕も君もあの人も
Me, you, and that person too
何でもないと言いながら
While saying it's nothing
心に重を君に背負わせる
Making you carry the weight in your heart
運命が通せんぼする
Fate is blocking the way
間違い　自業自得だよ
It's a mistake, you brought it on yourself
でも状況が良くないからね
But the situation isn't good
逃げたいよね
You want to run away, right?
生きたいよね
You want to live, right?
この体を投げ出すその瞬間が　あるとすれば
If there's a moment to throw this body away
この世の闇切り裂いてさ　ここに生まれた意味を探そうか
Tear through the darkness and find our purpose
終わりの始まり　始まれば最後さ　人生だから
The start of the end, once begun it's the finish
どうしようもない飛び出す背に　今しかない時があるのだろう
On that leaping back, there is a moment only now
雨に溺れることなんてさ　それほどないな
Drowning in the rain doesn't happen much
それでもなんだか息苦しいな
Even so, it feels somewhat suffocating
いつか死ぬために生きてるなんて
Living just so we can die someday
それならさ　それならば
If that's the case, if that's so
壊れない　壊れない　壊れない
Unbreakable, unbreakable, unbreakable
心の鐘を鳴らそう
Let's ring the bell of our hearts
曇天だろう　泥まみれさ
A cloudy sky, covered in mud
どこもかしこも
Everywhere and anywhere
今この世の行方を遮る迷路に　線を引こうぜ
Let's draw a line through this world's maze
その線がさ　重なる地図
That line becomes our overlapping map
君を照らすために咲く花さ
The flower blooming to light your way
A DREAM
Bae, you're on in five.
Never did she think she would be living out her wildest dream.
Good Luck!
BOOM
I come at just in time
Look what I got tonight
帳の降りた大路に　狂騒に集いな　午前二時は
On the dark road, gather in the frenzy at 2 AM
Dangerous stuff その瞬間に
Dangerous stuff, at that very moment
そのまず感覚　教えられないや
That first sensation, I can't teach it to you
Greetings, buddy!
One verse, 揺り動かすよ　見慣れた街並みを
One verse, I'll shake up these familiar streets
風を切る加速を　こちらサイドバックへ
Acceleration cutting through the wind, right here
Delicious, begin now　瞳を逸らすなよ Brother
Delicious, begin now, don't look away, Brother
正気じゃいられないね
You can't stay sane
Step the step, gotta down, 派手に行こう
Step the step, gotta down, let's go flashy
助手席に座れよ
Take a seat in the passenger side
心拍数が上がって止まらない
My heart rate is rising and it won't stop
火をつけたように　Never feel lucky
Like it's on fire, never feel lucky
ここのダンサー最高
This dancer here is the best
誇り高きPRIDE
A noble PRIDE
All-in, all-in, no backing out
Risk your life on it
Oh yes
And watch it go boom
We make it go boom
Oh yes
Ready for a watch it go boom
We make it go boom
Oh yes
Ready for a watch it go boom
Sorry don't care about it, it's my dirty mouth
今更クリンじゃヤダ聴けない
It's too late for "clean", I don't want to hear it
回しっぱ びごまーしなっ
Keep it spinning, big machine
頭の固叩き込みな
Hammer it into your thick head
Size of my line
Small market killer
ちょっとそこの丸そこどけやハイランダライバル
Hey you over there, get out of the way, highlander rival
So get ready favor
ババビズ ガッタドゥガナヨ
Ba-ba-biz, gotta do gotta go
ガッタドゥガナヨ
Gotta do gotta go
助手席に座れよ
Take the passenger seat
心拍数が上がって止まらない
My heart rate is rising and won't stop
火をつけたように
Like it's been set on fire
Baby feeling
このチェンジャー最高
This changer is the best
狂気ならプライド
If it's madness, it's pride
Hold in, hold in, no backing out, risk your life on this
And watch it go boom
We make it go boom
Oh yes
Ready for a watch it go boom
We make it go boom
Hey hey
Ready for a watch it go boom
You win, you win, you always got a shot
一期一会これだから
Once-in-a-lifetime encounter, that's why
走るぜ
I'm running!
RXRXR
あぁ、もう嫌だって顕著に絶望
Ah, clearly despairing of being sick of it already
溜め込んだ痛みここで撤去
Removing the accumulated pain right here
誰も知らないドブネズミの歌、騒いで聴かせましょう
A song of a sewer rat that no one knows, let's make a fuss and let them hear it
OKAY
SOMETHING NEW
不意な異色カッコいいわ僕の正体
Unexpectedly unique, my true self is cool
脱、あつりょくに屈した皆参戦
Breaking free, everyone who bowed to pressure, join the battle
They want a revolution?
Ha, we'll give it to 'em
Take a stand now, my wish is your command
You want a party? Follow behind me
カオスへと御招待
An invitation to chaos
急がなきゃ置いてかれるかもな気をつけてな
Hurry up or you might be left behind, so be careful
ROGUE RAT RUNAWAY
Got to get out of this place, 終わらせない
Got to get out of this place, I won't let it end
ROGUE RAT RUNAWAY
自由を逆手に果てしない世界
Turning freedom to my advantage, an endless world
ROGUE RAT RUNAWAY
I will stay in my own lane, 止まらない
I will stay in my own lane, I won't stop
ROGUE RAT RUNAWAY
本能を信じろいつだって
Trust your instincts, always
風のように
Like the wind
霞むように
Like a mist
We'll vanish into the night
誰も見ちゃいない 今に見てなさい
No one is watching, so watch me now
僕は世間の奴の鼻つまみもの
I'm a nuisance to the rest of the world
They want a way? Go far away
当たり捲れ
Hit them one after another
They say I'm a loser
Too bad I've heard it all before
My music, so money
Tell me that the melodies we play that makes your heart boom
Start up the party, we gon' get busy
ノイズが邪魔をしても
Even if noise gets in the way
隙は見せたくはあれちゃうぞ
I won't show any weakness
ROGUE RAT RUNAWAY
I will keep you on your feet, 油断しないで
I will keep you on your feet, don't let your guard down
ROGUE RAT RUNAWAY
Always keep you guessing, 惑わせて
Always keep you guessing, confusing you
知らず知らず秩序乱す
Unknowingly disturbing the order
...into the night
Hey!
Ladies and gentlemen!
The Baelday is now a rage!
地球はどこなの
Where is the Earth?
僕に価値はあるの
Do I have any value?
現実を壊せば
If I break reality,
そこはシャングリラ
it's a Shangri-la there.
Let's go!
Rogue Rat Runaway
Gotta get out of this place...
...止まらない
...I can't stop.
Rogue Rat Runaway
忠誠 逆転 反転 世界
Loyalty, reversal, inverted world.
Rogue Rat Runaway
Yeah won't you say my name 詰まらない
Yeah won't you say my name, it's boring.
Rogue Rat Runaway
本能知っちゃうボーイ 付いて来て
The boy who knows instinct, follow me.
風のように
Like the wind,
霞むように
like the haze,
We'll vanish into the night
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Did you like it?
I told you there was not going to be any time for breaks.
It was going to be song after song after song after song!
I hope you enjoyed it.
We had a lot of guest songs,
and I'm so happy and honored that I was able to perform with so many members
that I look up to and that have helped me so much on my idol journey.
I could cry!
But the last thing that you heard was something very special.
Did you know... I just came out with a new song!
What? That last song was a new song? What?
なんのど！？ オリジナルソング？
What!? Original song?
Yes, that's right. The last song I just sang called RXRXR
is my new original,
and the music video will be coming out after the stream, so please do check it out.
But that's actually not the major announcement.
Did you think that was the major— no.
The actual major announcement is what comes with the song.
Tan-tan-tan-tan! Little Rat has been cooking,
Ta-da! Little Rat has been cooking,
and I bring you my first album: ZODIAC!
My first album is finally out.
It consists of 13 brand new songs. 13!
Not one, not two... 13 brand new songs,
ZODIAC by yours truly, Hakos Baelz.
I've been working on this for so long, and it has cost me blood, sweat, and tears,
but it's finally out.
The digital version will be available at midnight at your local time.
I'll be doing a first listen at midnight JST tonight.
So make sure you go and check out that stream, maybe you can come listen to it with me.
But for those who like physical... physical, physical, physical CD sets,
yes, there's a physical CD that will be available for purchase after this stream as well.
And there's also a ZODIAC-themed fan!
There's a fan, ご覧よ！
There's a fan, look!
カッコよくない？ It's so cool.
Isn't it cool? It's so cool.
It's like a— it's an exclusive fan that has the art from the album cover,
and I think it's so cool and you can like use it to decorate your own desk space
or whatever you want to put it. I think it's really cool.
So please do support it, I worked really, really hard and I can't believe I can say it.
My first album, ZODIAC, is now out. Soon. Will be out soon.
Yes, but I can announce it!
Okay, calm down. If you think that was the end of Shio-taro, no.
There's more! I bring you...
Tan-tan-tan-tan! Hakos Baelz 2024 Birthday Merch!
Ta-da! Hakos Baelz 2024 Birthday Merch!
Because I don't know if you know, it's my birthday!
It's my birth— eh?
Wait, what? Wait, wait, wait... eh?
Staff has told me... what? Eh? Wait...
Apparently I have a video message from someone.
Eh? Wait, seriously? まじ？ Wait...
Eh? Wait, seriously? Seriously? Wait...
Hold on, this is not part of the plan. Eh? Okay...
I don't know who it's from.
親愛なるハコス・ベールズ殿、
My dear Fräulein Hakos Baelz,
お誕生日おめでとう。
I bid you a happy birthday.
新たな年齢を迎えることが、
I pray that this milestone
貴殿の更なる成長と成功につながるよう、
brings with it even greater growth and success for you.
私も心から祈っている。
I also pray for this from the bottom of my heart.
きっと素晴らしい1年になることだろう。
This coming year will surely be a momentous one.
ああ、もちろん、
Of course,
日々の研鑽は怠らぬように。
I trust you will not shirk your regular studies.
ということで、ハコスちゃん、Wassup!
And so, Hakos-chan, wassup!
初めまして、声優の悠木碧です。
Nice to meet you, I'm voice actress Yuki Aoi.
どうもー
Hello—
悠木 碧
Yuki Aoi
悠木碧です。
I'm Yuki Aoi.
改めて、この度はお誕生日おめでとうございますー！
And once again, a very happy birthday to you!
実は、ハコスちゃんのことはですね、インターネットを通じて私も少し前から存じ上げておりました。
Actually, I've known about you, Hakos-chan, for a while now through the internet.
何でも、私もね、ターニャ・フォン・デグレチャフ役で参加させていただいているアニメ『幼女戦記』を大好きでいてくれているというね、噂を耳にした時はね、とっても嬉しかったです。
When I heard rumors that you love the anime "The Saga of Tanya the Evil," in which I play the role of Tanya von Degurechaff, I was very happy.
ねえ、言葉の壁を乗り越えて、ハコスちゃんの目と耳、そして心にもね、自分の携わる作品が届いて、愛していただけているなんて感激です。
I'm moved that a work I'm involved in reached your eyes, ears, and heart, crossing the language barrier, and that you love it.
いつか一緒にね、『Los! Los! Los!』が歌えたらいいなーなんて思っちゃいました。
I thought it would be nice if we could sing "Los! Los! Los!" together someday.
これからも、可愛いカオスを世界に振りまく素敵なネズミさんでいてください。
Please continue to be the wonderful mouse who spreads cute chaos to the world.
本当にお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, happy birthday!
悠木碧でした。バイバーイ！
This was Yuki Aoi. Bye-bye!
待って、待って待って待って... Time, time, wait, what, what?
Wait, wait wait wait... Time, time, wait, what, what?
Can I rewind to...
もう、ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
もう、神。もう、声。もう...
Already a god. Already that voice. Already...
お願い、もう、死んでいい。もう、ありがとうございます。
Please, I can die happy now. Thank you so much.
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, really!
Ah, I... I have no words.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
本当、Thank you.
Really, thank you.
I am the biggest Yuki fan, and I just want to cry.
ターニャ大好き！ありがとうございました。
I love Tanya! Thank you so much.
I will, I want to... I don't... I can't speak. I...
Thank you.
Thank you so much for making this happen.
悠木碧さん！
Yuki Aoi-san!!
Okay, where am I? What do I do now? Where was I?
Oh, okay, I just had a... okay.
So, I have birthday merch.
I have birthday merch.
Birthday Merch Complete Set
I'm kind of shook right now. You may be shook too by what you see.
But hey, I have birthday merch, and I'm coming out with a dakimakura.
#SleepWellBae Body Pillow Cover
I'm in shock, but maybe you'll be in shock too because I said I was never doing this.
But hey, it turns out this is a birthday that I've always dreamed of.
And hey, it's a birthday you've always dreamed of, because now you get a dakimakura...
...which I said I was never gonna do.
But hey, it's pretty cute, you should get it.
It's very realistic, this is what I look like when I wake up in the morning.
I also have a second good... what else did I make? I don't know, my brain's off.
Oh, I made Apple & Bae-nanas fridge magnets.
#Apples&Bae-nanas Rubber Magnet Set
They're pretty cute, you should get that too.
You can put the stuff on the fridge.
They're pretty cute, you should get it.
I think I had one more item. I had a phone strap.
#BaeNeedsOne Smartphone Shoulder Strap
Bae needs oxygen right now. And also a phone strap...
...because it's good for travel.
Yeah, it's very handy, you should get it.
And also, I have a situation voice.
Voice Pack
Situation Voice Pack "29.02.2024"
It is a very special message for my brat and for myself in four years' time.
Yeah, you should get it.
Also, normally there is limited goods, but there aren't any this year...
Complete Set Purchase Bonus
Postcard with a handwritten autograph.
...because I decided I'm gonna sign every single person's postcard...
...if you buy the full set!
You only get a birthday once every four years, and you know what?
I think you all deserve it.
I don't care if my hand falls off. If you buy the full set, you are guaranteed a signed postcard.
はい、フルセット買ってくれる方はみんな直筆サイン入りポストカードもらえます！はい！
Yes, everyone who buys the full set will get a hand-signed postcard! Yes!
ありがとうございました、本当にいつも。
Thank you very much, really, for everything.
Hi, thank you so much for supporting me.
Please get it. There is no limited sale, only the limited period.
The entire merch is available, so you don't have to rush to get in line.
You can just get it within the normal sale period.
Yeah.
Thank you, よろしくお願いします。
Thank you, please look forward to it.
That is all for today. I'm gonna go cry now.
I hope that was good.
Bye! I'm gonna go... what just happened? Oh my god, I need water. Okay, bye.
Who was that I heard?
Did you want an encore?
My heart is still shaking...
...but it's okay!
Because we still have one more song.
We have time for one more song until the end of the show.
I wanted to finish off with a bang!
Um, and I would like to perform one more song for you guys as the encore song.
And it's a very important song to me, very special to my heart.
So I hope you'll listen.
はい、どうぞ！ かくれんぼ！
All right, here it is! Kakurenbo!
いっせーので鳴り響く　スタートの合図
Ready, set, go! The signal to start rings out
点と線で結んだ世界　色づいていくここから
The world connected by dots and lines begins to take on color from here
かくれんぼ
Lyrics: TKT Composition: EREN
Kakurenbo
転んで転がる頃　既にここにあった
By the time I tumbled and rolled, it was already right here
僕じゃない誰かの記憶が　呼び人と共に蘇る
Someone else's memories, not mine, resurface along with the one calling
古ぼけた絵本を取り出して
Taking out an old, worn-out picture book
落書きの中に一つの　答えを見つけた
Among the scribbles, I found a single answer
自分の価値に目を疑って　どこまでだって落ちていけるの
Doubting my own worth, wondering how far down I can fall
どこか遠くに消えてしまいたい　こんな世界じゃ僕は要らない
Wanting to disappear somewhere far away, I'm not needed in a world like this
カウントダウンが始まっているよ
The countdown has already begun
いっせーので声を上げて　聞こえてくるんだ
Ready, set, shout! I can hear it coming
自分の影の長さに気付く　もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my own shadow, it's already that time
一等星が顔を出した　届きそうで手を伸ばした
A first-magnitude star peeked out, I reached out my hand as if it were within reach
次は僕についてきなよと　どんな暗闇でも
"Follow me next," even in the darkness
もういいかい？
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet
幕は上がり出した
The curtain has begun to rise
もういいかい？
Are you ready?
まーだだよ
Not yet
色づいていくここから
Taking on color from here
10年後の僕らは　すれ違いばかりで
Ten years from now, we'll probably just be passing each other by
幻想に思いを馳せては　戻れないそう思い込んだ
Lost in fantasies, I convinced myself there was no going back
くたびれた心に追いつきを　あの頃と変わらない夕陽も
Catching up with my worn-out heart, even the sunset hasn't changed since then
なんとも思わない
I don't feel a thing
自分を信じ歩いていければ　どこまでだって登れるのに
If I could just believe in myself and keep walking, I could climb to any height
あどけなくその空白に　大切なもの見落としている
In that blank space, I'm overlooking something important
見つけられないと泣き喚く君へ
To you, who cries out that you can't find it
いっせーので声を上げて　聞こえてくるんだ
Ready, set, shout! I can hear it coming
自分の影の長さに気付く　もうこんな時間だ
Noticing the length of my own shadow, it's already that time
一生懸命駆け抜ける君　俯いてただけの僕でも
You, who runs through it all, even for someone like me who just hung my head
君の前を歩けるから　こんな頼りない僕でも
I can walk ahead of you, even if I'm this unreliable
宝箱は埃を　被ったまま失くした
The treasure chest was lost, still covered in dust
鍵はずっと君の　ポケットの中にあった
The key was in your pocket all along
散らばっていた全てが　今一つに重なる
Everything that was scattered now overlaps as one
手を取り始めよう　僕たちの物語
Let's take hands and begin our story
もう一回は
I thought
いらないと思ってた
I didn't need one more time
湿ったままで
I felt like I could
胸を張れる気がしたんだ
hold my head high even while wet
全てが愛おしくて
Everything is so precious
思い出に重なる
The cheers that overlap
掛け声はいつも
with memories are always...
でいっせーのーで声を上げて
So on the count of three, raise your voice!
いっせーのーで声を上げて
On the count of three, raise your voice
聞こえてくるんだ
I can hear it
自分の影の長さに気づく
I notice the length of my shadow
もうこんな時間だ
it's already this late
愛おしさが顔を出した
Preciousness showed its face
孤独色で手を伸ばした
I reached out with the color of loneliness
次は僕に付いてきなよと
Follow me next time
暗闇を歩もう
let's walk through the darkness
もういいかい？
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet
泣きじゃくった声で
with a sobbing voice
もういいかい？
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet
笑う君が見えた
I saw you laughing
もういいかい？
Are you ready?
まだだよ
Not yet
泣く僕を連れ出して
take me out as I cry
もういいかい？
Are you ready?
もういいよ
I'm ready
色付いていくここから
from here it starts to gain color
Hey!
Thank you!
This has been the best birthday ever!
Thank you for the best bday ever! Without you guys I never would have come this far. This Rat will continue doing her best! -BAELZ